A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grant-Funded Publications FA1715
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Grant-Funded Publications
1980-1992
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1715
1.9 Cubic Feet 5 letter document containers
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into four series:
1. National Poetry Series - Grant No. 08350213
2. Council on Foreign Relations - Grant No. 08600731
3. Princeton University - Grant No. 08350080
4. The Regents of the University of California, Los Angeles - Grant No. 09050983
Biographical / Historical
Most of the books in this collection were published with the support of the National Poetry Series. The Ford Foundation provided a grant to the Cultural Council Foundation to help establish The National Poetry Series in 1978. The grant continued through 1986. The National Poetry Series supports the publication of five books of poetry every year selected from an open competition.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains books that were published with the support of Ford Foundation grants. The majority of books in this collection are from the National Poetry Series. Established in 1978, the National Poetry Series is a literary awards program that supports the publication of five books of poetry every year selected from an open competition.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2019 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as part of Accession 2019:097 (Box 039979)
Ford Foundation
- National Poetry Series - Grant No. 08350213, 1980-1987; 1; 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the author
  Scope and Contents
  Ford Foundation Grant No. 08350213 provided $50,000 to the National Poetry Series between 1983-1986 for efforts to foster development of poetic talent.
  - Second Sight, Jonathan Aaron, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Junk City, Barbara Anderson, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gumbo, George Barlow, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Afterwards, Amy Bartlett, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - In the Solar Wind, Wendy Battin, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Collected Poems of Sterling A. Brown, Sterling Brown, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Mud Actor, Cyrus Cassells, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Black Dog, Red Dog, Stephen Dobyns, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Living Gloves, Lynn Doyle, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Local Time, Stephen Dunn, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cardinals in the Ice Age, John Engels, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Raft, Kathy Fagan, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Persistence of Memory, Mary Fell, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - God's Mistress, James Galvin, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Incognito Lounge, Denis Johnson, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ark 50 Spires 34-50, Ronald Johnson, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Wild Onion, Robert L. Jones, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Going On, Joanne Kryger, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Any Body's Song, Joseph Langland, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Dollmaker's Ghost, Larry Levis, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Eroding Witness, Nathaniel Mackey, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - The Greater Leisures, Jane Miller, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Cities in Motion, Sylvia Moss, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Hugging the Jukebox, Naomi Shihab Nye, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Denizens, Ronald Perry, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Leaving Taos, Robert Peterson, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - From the Abandoned Cities, Donald Revell, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - In Winter, Michael Ryan, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Folly River, Wendy Salinger, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - So This is the Map, Reg Saner, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Accidental Weather, Sherod Santos, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Silver and Information, Bruce Smith, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Red Roads, Charlie Smith, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Silks, Roberta Spear, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - The Hands in Exile, Susan Tichy, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Corpse and Mirror, John Yau, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Council on Foreign Relations - Grant No. 08600731, 1988-1990; 2; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Ford Foundation Grant No. 08600731 provided $178,400 between 1986-1990 to the Council on Foreign Relations in support of a research project on U.S.-Canada trade negotiations.
  - Making Free Trade Work: The Canada-U.S. Agreement, Peter Morici (ed.), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Bilateralism, Multilateralism and Canada in U.S. Trade Policy, William Diebold, Jr. (ed.), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Princeton University - Grant No. 08350080, 1990; 3; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Ford Foundation Grant No. 08350080 provided $10,000 from 1982-1983 to Princeton University in partial support for a conference, "Kampuchea in the 1980s: Prospects and Problems"
  - The Cambodian Agony, David A. Ablin and Marlowe Hood, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- The Regents of the University of California, Los Angeles - Grant No. 09050983, 1992; 4; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Ford Foundation Grant No. 09050983 provided $17,277 between 1990-1992 to the University of California, Los Angeles in support for a handbook on economic development of Indian reservations.
  - What Can Tribes Do?: Strategies and Institutions in American Indian Economic Development, Stephen Cornell and Joseph P. Kalt (ed.), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 40)